

AVAILABILITY

Yes, I'm immediately available for work and/or willing to relocate



CALL ME

+971 50 340 3822



LIVING IN

Dubai, United Arab Emirates



EMAIL

ariflive.com@gmail.com



WEB

https://ariflive.com



PORTFOLIO

https://www.behance.net/ariflive



BIRTHDAY

September 1975



DEPENDENTS

I've wife and three kids



CAN SPEAK

English & Urdu



TRAVELLED ABROAD

Singapore • Malaysia • Thailand Oman • Qatar • Saudi Arabia Turkey • Georgia • Egypt • Sri Lanka Spain • France

Expertise

User Interface • User Experience • Branding

Photoshop • Illustrator • Animate • Dreamweaver

HTML5 • CSS3 • SCSS • SASS • LESS

JavaScript • jQuery • AngularJS • NodeJS

Wordpress • PHP • MySQL • phpMyAdmin

AJAX • JSON • RESTful API • Web Services • XML

Git • GitHub • GitLab • Apache • XAMPP • Jenkins



Arif Muhammad

UX Designer & Front-end Developer

I can handle a web or app from requirement gathering, project plan, logo design, branding, user interface, user experience, front-end and back-end development till the server deployment.

I'm flexible to learn any new technologies, adopt any trends, ready to face any challenges in different situations and have strong problem solving abilities.

Experience

Senior UX Designer @ Cobone

2011 - PRESENT

9+ years

• Collaborate on user experience planning with IT Director.

Dubai, United Arab Emirates - https://www.cobone.com

- Create mockups and prototypes on tight timelines.
- Develop complex front-end UX with JavaScript, HTML5, jQuery, CSS3 and Bootstrap.
- \bullet Implement web design principles to ensure that the company website renders well across multiple devices.
- Ensure technical feasibility of UI designs.
- Maintain graphic standards and branding throughout the product's interface.
- Optimize website for maximum speed and scalability.
- Provide website maintenance and enhancements.
- Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies.
- \bullet Working closely with back-end developers, business analysts to define & implement amazing web-delivered user experiences.

Web Designer & Developer @ Media World

2010 - 2011

Dubai, United Arab Emirates - https://www.mediaworld.ae

- Design user interfaces to internet applications.
- Development of web applications for customer facing systems.
- \bullet Maintenance of MySQL databases for use in external and internal applications.
- Interacting with the client for requirement gathering and project reporting.
- Define site objectives by analyzing user requirements, envisioning system features and functionality.
- Develop web solutions in a variety of third party frameworks Wordpress and Drupal.
- Linux / Apache web server administration.
- Supporting, maintaining and upgrading existing live sites.

Web Designer @ Qatar Airways

2009 - 2010

Doha, Qatar - https://www.qatarairways.com

- Oversee day-to-day execution of email campaigns from creative setup and html coding to testing and deployment via email service provider.
- Develop the JavaScript libraries and frameworks of public facing sites.
- Through campaign request form management, facilitate and monitor email campaign reporting
- Ensure that the brand experience integrated into all email campaigns in a way that is consistent with overall company brand objectives.
- Manage subscriber database, including creating and updating lists, working with database partners, and segmenting data for targeted email campaigns.
- Implement quality assurance processes to ensure accurate and on-time campaign delivery of emails.
- Contributes to the design of email campaigns and programs to those specifications.

Web Master @ Depa United Group

2008 - 2009

Dubai, United Arab Emirates - https://depa.com

- Create web applications using ASP.NET, JavaScript, ActionScript and Visual Studio to increase staff effectiveness and performance.
- \bullet Ensure that the brand experience integrated into all campaigns in a way that is consistent with overall company brand objectives.
- Re-writing the web modules in ActionScript object oriented programming.
- Developing unit tests, integration tests and deployment scripts.
- Collaborate with team members to ensure web application is capable of meeting strategic aims of the core business.
- \bullet Troubleshoot and support live web application to the end-users.
- Performing web server setup and deployment.

Social Links



LINKEDIN @ariflive



FACEBOOK



@ariflivecom



TWITTER

@ariflivecom



GITHUB

@ariflive

Knowledge

React • ECMAScript 6 • Vue • Backbone • Ember

ASP .NET • C# • Java • Grails • Groovy • Objective-C

OOP Concept • Algorithm • Compilers • Databases

Research • A/B Testing • Analytics • Optimize

InVision • Sketch • Adobe XD



Arif Muhammad UX Designer & Front-end Developer

Brands

Recently working:

https://www.cobone.com

https://www.expatwoman.com/ewmoda https://www.expatwoman.com/ewmums https://www.expatwoman.com https://www.croutique.com

https://www.expatwoman.com/ewfood

Worked on:

https://qatarairways.com https://www.depa.com http://cmsglobal.com http://www.almeerathparts.com http://www.emiconglobal.com https://www.ufone.com

https://kalsoft.com

http://www.mass.com.pk

https://www.axiomtelecom.com https://binhaideradvocates.com

https://partymood.ae https://toolsforcake.com https://www.ninaiskander.com https://globalminds.co.in https://creativechaos.co https://appna.org

2009

2008

Education, Certification & Award

1st Price Winner, Cover & T-shirt Design

APPNA, California, United States

Adobe Photoshop CS3 Certification

Brain Bench, United States

Diploma of Information Technology 2001

Petromen, Karachi, Pakistan

Bachelor of Commerce 1996

Karachi University, Karachi, Pakistan

References

Mr. Hammad Khan

Group Marketing Head, Meraas Group Dubai, United Arab Emirates

+971 56 378 9933

Mr. Xavier Fernandes

IT Director, Cobone Dubai, United Arab Emirates

+971 55 954 7176